

MD CHANCHAL BISWAS

Web Developer

SKILLS

Language

- 1. PHP [00P & MVC]
- 2. Javascript
- 3. SQL
- 4. C++
- 5. Java

Framework & Library

- 1. Codelgniter
- 2. Laravel
- 3. jQuery

Database

- 1. MySQL
- 2. SQLite

Design

- 1. HTML5
- 2. CSS
- 3. Bootstrap

Software

- 1. PhpStorm
- 2. Sublime Text 4
- 3. Visual Studio Code
- 4. Visual Studio
- 5. Eclips

os

- 1. macOS
- 2. Windows

Testing & DevOps

- 1. Unit Testing
- 2. Github

Education

SSC (Science) - 2013-2014 Nagarkandi SP Secondary School, Bagerhat

Diploma (CSE) - 2016-2021 Jashore Polytechnic Institute, Jashore

Graduation (CSE) - 2021- Running Northern University of Business and Technology, Khulna

CONTACT

Address

Road No #07, Nirala R/A, Khulna 9100, BD

Phone

+880 1707093920

Email Address mchanchalbd@gmail.com

Githuk

Username: net-chanchal

Linkedin

Username: net-chanchal

Website

www.chanchal.ne

PROFILE

I'm Chanchal Biswas. I'm web developer. Computer programming is my passion. So far I have eight years of experience in professional web programming. I always use time complexity, memory complexity, algorithm simplification, security and coding style very seriously in each of my web applications.

WORK EXPERIENCE

I've finished lots of projects as a freelancer. Some of them are mentioned below.

Inventory Management System

kundutraders.com | 2023

PHP (Laravel v9.x), MySQL Stored Procedure

This system has been developed specifically as per the requirements of the company. They have a lot of data.

OpenAl Messenger

ai.kundutraders.com | 2023

PHP (OOP), SQLite, Javascript, OpenAl API

It has created a messenger for chatting that is used by the OpenAI API.

University Management System

2023

PHP (Laravel v9.x), MySQL Stored Procedure

It is a complete university management system still in its work in progress.

University Routine Management System

2022

C++ (For Windows Platform), Java (For Android Platform), MySQL, PHP (for API Development)

It was the University's routine management system and was done separately for Windows and Android platforms. It was a personal test project.

Foundation

aaronbarnettfoundation.org | 2020-2022

PHP (Codelgniter), MySQL, Javascript

This is a foundation's website. It is very big and has a lot to do. It has been developed for a long time. (Rubric System, Board Member, Scholarship and etc)

E-Commerce

pryme.org | 2020-2022

PHP (Codelgniter), MySQL, Javascript

It was a large ecommerce system. I worked for more than two years. Included (Multi Vendors, Dealers, Retailers, Shipping (UPS, USPS), Multiple Payment Gateway, RMA, Product Series and etc.

Store Locator

vendorlocator.7eye.com | vendorlocator.zienaeyewear.com | 2022

Codelgnite, MySQL, Javascript (Javascript was use for work like React JS)

It was originally developed using the Google API to find all of the company's stores.

Blog

thinkschool.org | 2021

PHP (Codelgniter), MySQL

This is a largest informative website. A large portion of YouTube videos is linked to it.

Result Management System

govtmuhsincollege.edu.bd | 2019

PHP, MySQL, Javascript

It was developed for a college's results management and it included a website.

Property Management System

lpmukltd.com | 20218

PHP, MySQL, Javascript

A company had a property management system through which they manage all their properties.

Digital Agency

webbang.co.uk | 2018

PHP (Codelgniter), MySQL

It's a digital agency website. This website provide Domain, Hosting, Website Design and Development.

API Used Skill

- 1. Google Map API (Distance Matrix API, Maps Javascript API, Geocoding API, Places API)
- 2. MapBox API
- 3. Payment Gateway: Authorize.net, PayPal, Stripe
- 4. OpenAl